So in the previous video we have seen how to update data blocks.
And in this video we are going to see how to update sector trailers and how to change the key A and
key B's.
So the tool we are going to use is Easy key, which also comes with the same SDK.
So over here there is easy key.
You just have to click and the tool will be open.
So the reader connection is the first option how you are going to make the connection.
So we are going to make the connection using PC slash SC.
So let's just click on it and you will get the reader name.
So over here, one, two, two is the only reader which is connected.
You can see it over here as well.
So we are just going to select this.
And the tool will connect.
The next screen is current logging parameters so you can log in with key A or key B, It depends on
your access conditions, right?
So our access condition is on transport configuration.
So we can log in with key A and the default key is f, f, f, f, f, f, f, f, f, f and f f.
So we are going to log in with this key.
This is the default key.
And over here, there is a sector decimal.
So this tool accepts data in decimal.
It's written over here.
So you you have to give only the sector number.
So there are 16 sectors in each mifare classic card, as I told you before.
So if you have to change the sector keys of key sector one, then you have to provide sector one over
here.
If you want to change the keys of sector zero, you can provide sector zero.
Similarly, if you want to change the sector keys of sector 16, which is the last sector or sorry sector
15 because we start from zero.
So method classic one cards has 0 to 15 sectors, so you can provide 15 over here if you want to update
the last sector.
Right.
So this is the sector decimal.
And over here there is new key A.
New option base and new keeb.
So after logging with any key, let's just suppose we log in with key A If you want to change key A,
you can provide a new key over here.
And if you want to update option bits or the access conditions or the access bits, all three are same.
You can change it over here and you can update key B similarly over here.
All right.
So we will first update the sector keys of Sector one because we have written data in Sector one.
So let's just update the key of sector one as well.
So let's just make our keys real simple to remember.
So we will update our new key with the last two bytes.
So I'll do a.
And a over here and let's just do format sector.
And it's quite fast.
And you can see over here, right.
Data to block three.
And this is the data which is written.
Why you think write data to block three.
Because block three is a sector trailer.
You can see it over here in each sector.
Block three is a sector trailer.
You can see this in-memory structure of mifare classic one card as well.
So right data is successful.
Now let's just try to do format sector one more time.
Nothing.
Authenticate or fail to authenticate to sector one.
Why is that?
We just authenticated successfully.
But now it's not authenticating.
It is because we have changed our key and we are logging with key A.
So in Mifare classic card, as I told you before, in Mifare classic card, you have to whatever action
you want to do.
Either you have to read data, write data, or update data.
You have to log in or you have to authenticate each time.
So over here we authenticated with key A, which was the correct key before and then we changed key
A.
Now again, we want to format data or we again want to update something.
We have to again log in.
And because we have changed the key A and we are logging with the old key, it's not going to log in.
Right.
So we have to update key A over here as well.
And let's just do format sector one more time.
So now it's able to write data to block three.
Successfully.
And now let's just update KB as well.
So I'll update the last two bytes.
And I'll do B, B and B over here.
So it's simple to remember and I'll do format sector one.
So it's able to format the data so key A and B are updated on sector one.
Right.
There is option bits as well.
You can update option bits as well.
So right now we are using transport configuration, but if you want to update each block configuration,
let's suppose you just want to read data and never write.
You can use this configuration.
This is the same table which we have described in our previous video.
So over here you can see you can update this table over here and it will automatically adjust the bits
over here.
So if you want to change the configuration to read, write, block or read from key A or B or when we
will see later in our video how to create value blocks.
And you want to just increment with key and decrement with key B, you can do all the configuration
over here.
This type of configuration.
All right.
So I'll keep my settings to transport configuration of access bits for now, but you can update all
the access bits as well from the same easy key management tool.
So we have changed our keys for now.
Let's just close this tool and let's just log in.
On our 1 to 2 you tool one more time.
Connect and let's just get data.
So this is our Uuid, the same Uid we are getting and let's just do get attr.
And let's just authenticate with the default key, which was the transport configuration key and hit.
Okay.
And let's just try to authenticate block four.
And if you see, block four is in Sector one, and we have updated the keys of sector one.
So it shouldn't be able to authenticate this.
Block Right?
So let's just check out this first.
So as you can see, it's saying Operation Field.
Right.
So let's just try to authenticate block five as well with the same key, not able to authenticate block
five or authenticate block six.
It's not able to authenticate Block six as well.
And block seven.
It's saying authentication field, right?
If I authenticate Block eight, which is in Sector two over here, you can see Block eight is in Sector
two.
So it should be able to authenticate Block eight, right?
Because we haven't changed anything on Block on Sector two.
So it should be able to authenticate.
We have just updated the keys of sector one, so it should be able to authenticate all the other blocks
with the transport configuration.
So let's just do authenticate Block eight.
So you can see it's authentication success and we can read data block eight as well.
We can write data on block on block eight as well, but we are not able to get our data from Sector
one on which we have updated our keys.
So let's just authenticate or load the first, let's just load the correct keys.
So I'll authenticate with key A on zero zero.
You can provide any key and on one one you can provide a key B as well.
So first I'll just do key A and let's just try to authenticate with key A.
So over here you can see the message load authentication key success.
Now let's just try to authenticate block for.
And over here it's saying authentication success.
That means we have authenticated our block successfully.
Now, let's just read this block.
So you can see the hexadecimal data.
Let's just read this data in as well.
So you can see Hello World RFID.
This is the data which we have written in our previous video.
Now let's just authenticate block five as well from the same key.
And let's just read this block.
In Ascii format.
So over here you can see this is my message.
One reading the blog successfully.
Now let's just read the sector trailer block as well.
So let's just authenticate.
Block seven, which is our sector trailer from Sector One.
And seeing authentication success.
Let's just read this block.
So over here, as you can see, we are not able to read Key A and I have told you the reason why we
are not able to read Key A, but we are able to read the access bits successfully and we are also able
to read our.
Keep as well.
So as you can see, we have updated our key using easy key tool and we are easily able to read our key
because we are on a transport configuration right now.
We haven't changed anything on our access bits, so that's why we are able to read key as well.
But in few conditions, if we change the access bits, we can also not able to read key be in some condition.
We are we can even not read access bits as well.
So it all depends on your program and it all depends on your requirements, basically what type of requirement
you are getting from the client.
Right?
So this is this all things depends on the client requirement, how you want to program your thing.
So right now I have kept it very simple so we can just understand how to program a classic cards.
So this is how you program keys and this is how you read data after changing the keys, right?
So in the next video, we are going to see how to create value blocks and how to do increment decrement
operations and how to write on value blocks, Right?
So this is what we are going to see in our next video.